liveaccounts.com.au 2012-12-04

# MYOB Privacy Policy

##  MYOB Group Privacy Statement 

#### MYOB values your privacy

MYOB considers the guarding of your privacy as of the utmost importance. This **MYOB Group Privacy Policy** states our policy on maintaining your privacy and handling your personal information. Personal information means information about an identifiable individual.

This MYOB Group Privacy Policy relates to personal information we handle about our clients, visitors to our websites and other members of the public. Our personnel and job applicants can contact our human resources team for more information about their privacy. Online job applicants can also view the privacy policy at the [Opportunities@MYOB](http://www.bfound.net/list.aspx?CoId=1992&rq=5) recruitment website.

#### Reasons for collecting information

MYOB collects personal information which is necessary to conduct business with you.

MYOB and its service providers may use your personal or business information and information you have supplied for purposes including to:

  * identify you as the product owner and to provide better client service to you, your business partners and your employees
  * perform authorised financial transactions with you and your associated service providers
  * operate our business as it applies to you;
  * keep you informed about MYOB products and services and those of relevant business partners
  * participate in the process of any third party acquisition or potential acquisition of an interest in us or our assets
  * protect our lawful interests
  * fulfil legal and regulatory obligations

We may not be able to do these things, or those outlined below (under ‘How we use your information’), without your personal information. For example, we may not be able to manage your product registration or process transactions.

In certain circumstances we may collect ‘sensitive information’ about you such as your membership of a professional association (e.g. CPA status). Some privacy laws regulate the handling of sensitive information but may allow us to collect that information in some circumstances such as where you provide it voluntarily or otherwise consent to us collecting it.

#### How we use and disclose your information

MYOB uses and discloses your personal information and the information you supply in many ways necessary for us to do business together: product promotion, order fulfilment, product registration and company file activation, provide transactional services and client support and for secure access to MYOB websites.

##### **Product promotion**

MYOB may contact you about product upgrades and new product releases and to inform you of new services relevant to your business, including special offers. A number of laws are in place to limit direct marketing activity and you may notify us at any time that you do not want to receive any marketing communications from MYOB.

##### **Order fulfilment**

When ordering products and services, you must provide contact information (such as name, email address, phone number and delivery address) and financial information (such as credit-card number and expiration date if you are using this payment method). MYOB uses this information to fulfil your order and bill you. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is also used to get in touch with you to resolve the problem.

##### **Product registration**

MYOB asks you to register each product or service you purchase with relevant personal and business details. Registration ensures that only you - and no unauthorised persons - receive upgrades and special offers.

##### **Company File Activation**

MYOB asks you to activate each of the company files you create. During activation, information is sent by secure internet connection to MYOB to identify your product (this includes your serial number and the unique company file code for that company file), and to identify your business (your company name and ABN). MYOB then provides you with a confirmation code to complete activation, by internet access to MYOB’s website or by phone. The same process applies to periodic company file confirmations.

##### **Transactional Services**

To facilitate the provision of the transactional service for which you have applied MYOB is required to pass information you have provided to its service providers. See the section ‘Disclosures to third parties’ below for more on MYOB’s service providers.

##### **Client support**

Registration links your MYOB product and version to your contact details. This allows our support consultants to provide you with quality advice relevant to your particular situation when you call MYOB client support. If software or documentation needs to be emailed or posted to you, the consultant has all the information needed to ensure fast service.

##### **Aggregated data**

Aggregated data that contains no information specific to a particular individual or business may be shared with our business partners, for example, aggregated statistical trends in a particular industry sector.

##### **Disclosure to third parties**

We may provide your personal information to our related bodies corporate and our service providers who assist us with client contact, archival, auditing, accounting, legal, business consulting, banking, delivery, data processing, automated communications, website or technology services.

Some of the third parties described above including our service providers may be located in the United States, Singapore or other countries. You acknowledge that while these parties will often be subject to other confidentiality or privacy obligations, they may not in all cases be subject to the specific requirements of Australian or New Zealand privacy laws.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, facilitate court proceedings or to protect our rights.

#### **MYOB website access**

Many useful services are currently available at MYOB websites and more services are being planned. Your information gives you authorised access so that you can update your personal information, access online help or perform financial transactions. For some products, you may be able to authorise other people (such as your employees, accountant or bookkeeper) to access, input and manage information on your behalf.

Our web sites may contain links to other sites belonging to other parties and which are beyond the control of MYOB. Please note that we cannot vouch or be responsible for the privacy practices of non-MYOB sites.

MYOB also uses Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to analyse trends, administer our websites, track your navigation among MYOB web pages and gather broad information for aggregate use. Our web servers may also send cookies to your browser to track navigation history and ensure transaction pages, such as 'shopping cart' interactions, work correctly. Cookies contain only coded information that cannot be used by third parties to access your confidential information. Most browsers allow you to adjust settings to erase cookies, disallow cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is set. Please note that some parts of MYOB websites may not function fully for users that disallow cookies.

In some cases third parties may use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons and JavaScript on our Website in connection with online services like banner advertising, website analytics and surveys. This may allow them to collect information about your use of MYOB websites (including your computer’s IP address) which they may store in the United States or other countries. The use of these technologies allows them to deliver customised advertising content, measure the effectiveness of their advertising, evaluate users use of MYOB websites and other websites and provide other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Those third parties may also transfer the information they collect to others where required to do so by law, or where those others process the information on their behalf. The services we may use from time to time include Google Analytics, Google AdSense, DoubleClick, Yahoo, Adobe and Microsoft. You can find more details in the privacy policies for those services, including information on how to opt-out of certain conduct.

#### Security

Personal information that is held by MYOB is protected by a range of security measures. For example, MYOB web pages that request sensitive information may employ encryption technologies such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL).  
You can confirm that any MYOB data-entry page uses encryption by checking that:

  * the page address in the Web browser's tool bar or status bar begins with https://, or
  * the padlock icon in the web browser's tool bar or status bar is locked.

If you are considering sending us any personal information through unencrypted electronic means (e.g. standard email), please be aware that the information may be less secure in transit. We are subject to a number of laws requiring us to protect the security of personal information once it comes into our possession.

If you are a registered user of any MYOB website, access to your account may be controlled by a username and password chosen by you. To prevent unauthorised access, you should choose a strong password and keep it protected from others.

MYOB is also committed to protecting your information offline. All of your personal and business information, not just sensitive information, is subject to access controls.

#### Information access and correction

If you have any questions or concerns relating to this Privacy Policy, please contact the Privacy Officer in your local MYOB office. We will then use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine if there is a problem and take the necessary corrective action.

In the event that you need to access, update or correct your personal or business information, you can do so at [my.MYOB](https://my.myob.com.au/) for information available there. Alternatively, you can contact us to request access to or changes to your personal information. Please provide us with as much detail as you can about the particular information you are interested in, in order to help us locate it.

#### Feedback and concerns

Please contact us as set out below if you have any feedback or concerns about privacy. Where you express any concerns that we have interfered with your privacy, we will respond to let you know who will be handling your matter and when you can expect a further response.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Any changes to this Privacy Policy that may be made from time to time will be available on the MYOB website. You can also obtain a copy of the current Privacy Policy by either emailing or writing to the privacy officer in your local MYOB office.

#### Contacting MYOB

**AUSTRALIA  
Post:  
**Privacy Officer  
MYOB Australia Pty Ltd  
PO Box 371  
Blackburn VIC 3130  
**Phone:** 1300 555 128  
**Email:** [privacy_officer@myob.com.au ](mailto:privacy_officer@myob.com.au)

**Last updated: 26 September 2012**
